<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Entrepreneurship | Sean Mountcastle]]></title>
  <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/categories/entrepreneurship/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sean.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-16T00:11:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sean.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Mountcastle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smountcastle@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LaunchBox Unleashes Its First Nine Startups]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2008/08/06/launchbox-unleashes-its-first-nine-startups/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-06T08:28:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2008/08/06/launchbox-unleashes-its-first-nine-startups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over on TechCrunch they have a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/08/05/launchbox-unleashes-its-first-nine-startups/">great overview of the first nine startups</a> to come out of <a href="http://www.launchboxdigital.com/">LaunchBox Digital</a>, a local early stage investment firm. One of the founders of <a href="http://sharememe.com/">ShareMeme</a>, <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/luccastera">Luc Castera</a>, from the Ruby Users' Group (and local conferences). I'm excited to dig-in and start using these new services. Here's a brief overview:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.buzzhubb.com/">BuzzHubb: A Better College Social Network</a>. Next generation group management for colleges and universities (it is similar to Facebook in that regard &amp;emdash only students can join).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.heekya.com/">Heekya: The Wikipedia For Stories</a>. Social story telling using multiple forms of media (text, photos, video).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.jamlegend.com/">JamLegend: Guitar Hero Goes Social</a>. A free online music gaming experience.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.koofers.com/">Koofers: Crib Notes For Picking College Classes</a>. A tool to help students build their class schedules with insight into the classes, teachers, and styles as reported by other students. It also provides access to study guides, past exams, etc. to assist students.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mygamemug.com/">MyGameMug: Match.com For Gamers</a>. A personality test for gamers &amp;emdash find others who like the kinds of games that you do.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.razume.com/">Razume: Resume 2.0</a>. A tool for young (21-35) job seekers. This looks really interesting to me because I had a similar idea several years ago but never executed on it. I'm curious to see how its features overlap with my detailed plan.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sharememe.com/">ShareMeme: Evite Meets Twitter</a>. This service is addressing a real issue that is affecting me: being (inadvertently) spammed by my friends as they sign up for social networks and other services. If it succeeds it can be the go to point for distributing information out to your friends and family through the best channels.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.zadby.com/">Zadby: Web Video Product Placement</a>. Zadby wants to be the market maker for product placement in web video, through its network of independent web video producers.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startups 101]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2008/04/23/startups-101/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-23T23:58:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2008/04/23/startups-101</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://refresh-dc.org/"><img src="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/refreshdc.png" alt="Refresh
DC" /></a></p>

<p>Tonight I had the opportunity to attend a special <a href="http://refresh-dc.org/">Refresh
DC</a> meeting on the challenges of starting your
own business. The format was a panel of folks from the DC startup scene
moderated by <a href="http://www.viget.com/about/team/jwilkinson">Jackson
Wilkinson</a> of <a href="http://www.viget.com">Viget
Labs</a>. The panel consisted of <a href="http://www.viget.com/about/team/bwilliams">Brian
Williams</a> of Viget Labs,
<a href="http://andrewlee.com/">Andrew Lee</a> of <a href="http://publi.us/">Publi.us</a>,
Eric Rupert from <a href="http://odeo.com/">Odeo</a>, <a href="http://blog.hungrymachine.com/">Eddie
Frederick</a>of <a href="http://hungrymachine.com/">Hungry
Machine</a>, and <a href="http://www.launchboxdigital.com/blog.html">Sean
Greene</a> of <a href="http://www.launchboxdigital.com/">LaunchBox
Digital</a>.</p>

<p>These were the main points I took away:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Be passionate.</strong> The most important quality for startup founders
is to be passionate about their product or service. Starting a
company can be exhilarating but the setbacks can be really
difficult. If you're not passionate about what you're doing each of
these roadblocks will be an excuse for you to quit. Figure out what
you're passionate about and work on that.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on your product.</strong> Don't focus on the pie-in-the-sky
potential valuations of your company or worry about leasing office
space, hiring an attorney, finding an accountant, etc. Instead you
should focus on the product or service you're going to sell. Get
something out there quickly -- pick the most important feature and
get it out there in front of your customers quickly.</li>
<li><strong>Have your customers influence your product.</strong> If you follow the
previous advice and get your product out there quickly you can use
customer feedback to iterate your product. You may not know all of
the difference ways customers will use your product, so this
feedback is critical in charting your product roadmap.</li>
<li><strong>Equity is control, don't surrender it easily.</strong> One of the
attendees asked about using equity to pay for services if money was
tight. Brian said to avoid giving out equity as you make that person
a partner in your business. While they may not have a controlling
interest, they are still an owner and have some influence.</li>
<li><strong>Don't overfund.</strong> All of the panelists warned of the dangers of
taking too much money as it does more than dilute the founders'
ownership. Venture capitalists are looking to make a large return o
their capital for themselves and their limited partners. If you need
to pay a vendor or contractor find another way -- defer payment, use
credit, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Hire slow, fire fast.</strong> Early employees can make or break your
company. You will be working long hours aside these folks so you
must ensure they're a good fit. If you make a bad hire, you need to
resolve the situation quickly, don't let emotion get in the way.</li>
</ol>


<p>Some of the books recommended were: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Art-Start-Time-Tested-Battle-Hardened-Starting/dp/1591840562/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1209008603&amp;sr=8-1">Art of the
Start</a>,
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Yes-Negotiating-Agreement-Without/dp/0140157352/ref=pd_bbs_2?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1209008634&amp;sr=8-2">Getting to
Yes</a>,
and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Founders-Work-Stories-Startups-Early/dp/1590597141/ref=pd_bbs_3?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1209008603&amp;sr=8-3">Founders at
Work</a>.
Andrew also recommended <a href="http://startupschool.org/">Startup School</a> run
by <a href="http://ycombinator.com/">Y Combinator</a> (YC). I've been reading <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com">Paul
Graham</a>'s essays for around seven years now
and following YC's investments. I'm glad to see an early stage investor
like YC in the DC area (LaunchBox Digital) and hope that the startup
scene in DC and suburbs becomes more vibrant.</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://www.sainc.com/">Strategic Analysis</a> for hosting this.
It was a great venue and hope they'll offer to host Refresh DC again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startups in Northern VA]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/22/startups-in-northern-va/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-22T11:42:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/22/startups-in-northern-va</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I compiled this list several months ago when I was looking for work. In
the end, I decided to join an established company. I did not get a
chance to interview with each of the companies in the attached
spreadsheet, but I'll write separate posts about the ones that I did get
a chance to speak with. As a little bonus, here are the companies that I
know of in Northern Virginia working with the
<a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org">Ruby</a> programming language. Note that not all
of them are startups in the traditional sense:</p>

<ul>
<li>InfoEther (<a href="http://www.infoether.com">www.infoether.com</a>): This is
<a href="http://richkilmer.blogs.com/ether/">Rich Kilmer's</a> current startup
providing a secure and mobile digital vault on a USB drive. <a href="http://tomcopeland.blogs.com/">Tom
Copeland</a> also works at InfoEther.</li>
<li>CustomInk (<a href="http://www.customink.com">www.customink.com</a>): They have
an innovative web app for desigining logos, etc that can then be
printed on shirts, mugs, golf balls, pens, etc. They are currently
hiring.</li>
<li>Bosatsu Consulting (<a href="http://www.bosatsu.net/">www.bosatsu.net</a>):
Brian is working on some Ruby (non-Rails) projects and was looking
for someone to assist with Rails work--I don't know if he's found
anyone yet.</li>
<li>Digital Focus (<a href="http://www.digitalfocus.com">www.digitalfocus.com</a>):
This is a consulting company, primarily focusing on Agile
development (training, team insertion, etc). They are looking for
Ruby developers as the majority of their consultants are J2EE and
.Net folks.</li>
<li>Revolution Health Group
(<a href="http://www.revolution.com/health/default.asp">www.revolution.com</a>):
The Revolution suite of companies was founded in Washington, DC by
Steve Case (of AOL fame). The team at RHG is looking to tie together
several different healthcare acquisitions into a Ruby on Rails
portal. They've been trying to hire Ruby developers for quite awhile
now.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you know of any more companies with a focus on Ruby in the DC metro
area, please let me know about it via the comments. Here's the link to
the Excel spreadsheet containing the list of startups I found nearby. I
know for a fact that a few of the companies listed have already been
acquired. <a href="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/startups.xls">Startups in Northern
VA</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Y Combinator: The Top Internet VC Firms]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/21/y-combinator-the-top-internet-vc-firms/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-21T22:48:59-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/21/y-combinator-the-top-internet-vc-firms</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Paul Graham has an interesting piece up at Y Combinator entitled <a href="http://ycombinator.com/topvcs.html">The
Top Internet VC Firms</a>. This
provides a bit more insight into some of the VC's I mentioned in my
<a href="http://seanmountcastle.com/2006/11/15/qualified-investors-in-northern-va/">previous
post</a>
(many are definitely <strong>not</strong> top tier VCs--though I think this was
obvious before).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Qualified Investors in Northern VA]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/15/qualified-investors-in-northern-va/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-15T21:59:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2006/11/15/qualified-investors-in-northern-va</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know, I know--this post has a really lame title. I had wanted to call
it VC's which actively invest in the DC metro area but I've included
angels in this list as well. I've tried to be as thorough as possible,
but this research was done several months ago when I was looking for a
new job and desperately wanted to work at a startup. Unfortunately, I
was not willing to relocate and the number of startups in Northern VA
whose domains overlap with my interests and skills is rather low. So,
without any further ado, here's the list in no particular order:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.in-q-tel.com/" title="In-Q-Tel">In-Q-Tel</a> (VC fund, funded by
the intelligence community)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.walkerventures.com/" title="Walker Ventures">Walker Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.anthemcapital.com/" title="Anthem Capital">Anthem Capital
Management</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.nea.com/Home/" title="NEA">New Enterprise Associates</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.novakbiddle.com/" title="Novak Biddle">Novak Biddle</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.paladincapgroup.com/portal/index.php" title="Paladin Capital">Paladin Capital
Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.tridentcap.com/" title="Trident Capital">Trident Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.sasinvestors.com/home.html" title="SAS">SAS Investors</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.omidyar.net/" title="Omidyar Network">Omidyar Network</a> (Pierre
&amp; Pam Omidyar of eBay)<a href="http://www.omidyar.net/" title="Omidyar Network"></a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.redshiftventures.com/" title="RedShift Ventures">RedShift
Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.longworth.com/index_content.html" title="Longworth Venture Partners">Longworth Venture
Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.core-capital.com/" title="Core Capital">Core Capital Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.grotech.com/" title="Grotech Capital">Grotech Capital Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bluewatercapital.com/" title="Blue Water Capital">Blue Water
Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mavf.com/" title="MAVF">Mid-Atlantic Venture Funds</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.boulderventures.com/" title="Boulder Ventures">Boulder
Ventures</a>
(Primarily a Colorado investor, but also does deals in the
mid-atlantic)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.carlyle.com/eng/index.html" title="Carlyle Group">Carlyle
Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.inflectpoint.com/" title="Inflection Point Ventures">Inflection Point
Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.northhillventures.com/" title="North Hill Ventures">North Hill
Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.abscapital.com/" title="ABS Capital">ABS Capital Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.draperatlantic.com/" title="Draper Atlantic">Draper Atlantic</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.lazardtp.com/technologypartners/ltp_overview/ltp_overview.asp" title="Lazard Technology Partners">Lazard Technology
Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.intersouth.com/" title="Intersouth Partners">Intersouth
Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mvpfunds.com/" title="MVP Funds">Monumental Venture Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.tpgvc.com/index2.html" title="Texas Pacific Group">ACON
Ventures</a>
(an affiliate of Texas Pacific Group Ventures)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.edisonventure.com/" title="Edison Ventures">Edison Venture
Fund</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ecenturycapital.com/" title="Ecentury">Ecentury Capital
Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.colcap.com/" title="Columbia Capital">Columbia Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.tdfund.com/" title="Telecom Development Fund">Telecom Development
Fund</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.grosvenorfund.com/" title="The Grosvenor Funds">Grosvenor
Funds</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.friedlicorp.com/" title="Friedli Coporate Finance">Friedli Corporate
Finance</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.liquidcapitalgroup.com/" title="Liquid Capital">Liquid Capital
Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.valhallapartners.com/" title="Valhalla Partners">Valhalla
Partners</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.crosshill.com/" title="CrossHill Financial">CrossHill Financial
Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.washingtondinnerclub.com/" title="Washington Dinner Club">Washington Dinner
Club</a>
(angel investors)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newvantagegroup.com" title="New Vantage Group">New Vantage
Group</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.brv.com/" title="Blue Run Ventures">BlueRun Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.aurorafunds.com/" title="Aurora Funds">Aurora Funds</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.avansis.com/" title="Avansis Ventures">Avansis Ventures</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bcecapital.com/" title="BCE Capital">BCE Capital</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.opus8.com/" title="Opus8">Opus8</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.intel.com/capital/" title="Intel Capital">Intel Capital</a>
(Intel's VC arm, usually providers later stage funding).</li>
</ul>


<p>If you know of any more VCs/Angels in our area, please leave comments.
Also if you have opinions on any of these VCs, I'd be interested to hear
those as well. I've only dealt indirectly with two of the VCs from this
list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
