<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mobile | Sean Mountcastle]]></title>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/categories/mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-01T22:22:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Mountcastle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smountcastle@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AT&T Insanity]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/14/att-insanity/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-14T15:18:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/14/att-insanity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend <a href="http://blacka.com/david/">Dave</a> <del>is</del> was looking to get an
<a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> now that his <a href="http://blacka.com/david/archives/2007/07/the-irony/">Treo
died</a>. I already
have AT&amp;T service and I&rsquo;d love to upgrade to an iPhone as well. Being an
old AT&amp;T Wireless customer from before they were purchased by Cingular
and renamed (and now back to the old name) does not appear to be an
asset. I&rsquo;ve had the service before I was married, consequently if I&rsquo;m
going to upgrade my phone, consolidating my service with my wife&rsquo;s
through <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/easysetup/rateplans.html">AT&amp;T&rsquo;s family
plan</a> would
probably be best for us. Thus I called up AT&amp;T to see if they could
assist me. Unfortunately, my service is through the national business
accounts arm of the company and the family plan is not an option there.
I have no problem being switched off of the national business accounts
(and forgoing my monthly discount), but their system won&rsquo;t let them
convert my account. I can leave AT&amp;T and go to another service provider,
taking my number with me but I cannot stay with AT&amp;T and switch to the
family plan. If I leave to go to another carrier, taking my number with
me, and then go back to AT&amp;T, I&rsquo;ll still be stuck on the national
business accounts side of the house. The service representative said she
could set me up with a completely new account (i.e. new phone numbers)
with the family plan. I explained that I&rsquo;ve had my cell number for a
decade now and I&rsquo;m not going to change it. I&rsquo;m willing to pay them more
money (almost double what I pay now) and purchase one (possibly even
two) expensive handsets and they cannot help me out at all. This is
completely insane! AT&amp;T really needs to get its act together and
integrate its back office systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's on Russ's Nokia 6680?]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2005/06/14/whats-on-russs-nokia-6680/"/>
    <updated>2005-06-14T02:41:02-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2005/06/14/whats-on-russs-nokia-6680</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nokiausa.com/phones/6682/" title="Nokia 6682"><img src="http://www.nokiausa.com/images/phn/62x62/ph_6682_sml.gif" alt="Nokia
6682" /></a>
<a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/">Russ</a> has posted a great piece
entitled <a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/1008503.html">What&rsquo;s on my Nokia
6680</a>. I&rsquo;ve been
interested in this phone since I first heard about it several months ago
and it looks like Cingular is finally going to start selling the
<a href="http://www.nokiausa.com/phones/6682/">6682</a> version shortly. The great
part about Russ&rsquo;s post is the list of all of the applications available
for the Series 60 phones. I wasn&rsquo;t even aware of several of them. Though
my personal favorite is the <a href="http://www.wildpalm.co.uk/SuperGoBoy.html">Super
GoBoy</a> from
<a href="http://www.wildpalm.co.uk">WildPalm</a>. Being able to play your GBC games
on your phone is just incredible. And playing your old NES games is even
better (using <a href="http://www.vampent.com/vnes.htm">vNes</a>)! If you&rsquo;re
interested in writing games for the Series 60, then the open source
<a href="http://fb-s60.sourceforge.net/">Frozen Bubble</a> is a great place to
learn from as all of the source code is available at
<a href="http://www.sourceforge.net/">SourceForge</a>. Take the time to go and read
through Russ&rsquo;s post, there&rsquo;s a bunch of great information there (both
about the 6680 and Series 60 apps in general).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nokia Announces N-series Phones]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2005/04/28/nokia-announces-n-series-phones/"/>
    <updated>2005-04-28T02:26:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2005/04/28/nokia-announces-n-series-phones</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.nokia.com/n91" title="Nokia N91"><img src="http://www.nokia.com/BaseProject/Sites/NOKIA_MAIN_18022/CDA/Categories/Phones/PhoneModels/_Content/_Static_Files/n91_pm_cs.jpg" alt="Nokia
N91" /></a></p>

<p>Nokia has announced their new
<a href="http://press.nokia.com/PR/200504/991467_5.html">N-series</a> phones. One
in particular, the N91, <a href="http://news.com.com/Nokia+to+launch+phone+that+stores+3,000+songs/2100-1034_3-5686974.html">stores 3,000
songs</a>.
First off, this is a naming change for Nokia since most of their
previous models (except for the N-gage) are designated by four digit
numbers (i.e. 6620, 3650, etc). Since the features of the N91 interest
me the most, I&rsquo;ll focus on that phone.</p>

<p>The N91 has the following interesting features:</p>

<ul>
<li>4GB hard drive</li>
<li>WiFi</li>
<li>2M pixel camera</li>
<li>USB 2.0 sync'ing</li>
<li>Stereo-mini jack (for headphones)</li>
<li>and it supports Microsoft&rsquo;s WMV, Apple&rsquo;s AAC (sans FairPlay), M4A
and MP3</li>
</ul>


<p>All in all a pretty darn sweet phone. They&rsquo;ve basically stuffed an iPod
mini into a Nokia phone. And WiFi support? That&rsquo;s amazing, I&rsquo;m curious
if this means VoIP support or a future firmware upgrade which enables
this. Though with some carriers (*cough* Verizon *cough*) crippling
Bluetooth, I wonder if the same fate is in store for WiFi. Plus since
this thing is so media/music friendly, it seems that there must be some
sort of iTunes-like store in the works &mdash; though I suspect the carriers
want to run these themselves and capture that additional revenue. Nokia
has also announced partnerships with several top-of-the-line audio
brands to make accessories for this phone
(<a href="http://www.sennheiser.com/">Sennheiser</a> head phones anyone?) I think
the carriers in North America need to wake-up and allow unlimited SMS
messaging and a reasonable amount of data transfer in all of their
plans. Having just got back from Italy, I&rsquo;ve seen the difference in how
they use their cell phones from SMS'ing like crazy to paying for items
(mostly vending machines) using their cell phone. If the carriers would
stop nickle-and-diming their customers there are whole revenue streams
which would open up for them as well as third parties (premium SMS
anyone?). Well, it looks like I&rsquo;ve strayed from my initial topic, so
I&rsquo;ll end this now. Send me your thoughts on the new phones from Nokia.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
