<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Training | Sean Mountcastle]]></title>
  <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/categories/training/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sean.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-16T00:11:34-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sean.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Mountcastle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smountcastle@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Advanced Ruby Studio]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/12/05/advanced-ruby-studio/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-05T23:54:04-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/12/05/advanced-ruby-studio</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in July I attended the <a href="http://pragmaticstudio.com/ruby/">Advanced Ruby
Studio</a> in Reston, VA. At the time I
had wanted to blog about it but my life suddenly became extremely busy
and I left my blog to languish for several months. To rectify that, I've
decided to write up this post providing an overview of the studio and my
impressions. The instructors for the three day course were <a href="http://pragdave.blogs.pragprog.com/pragdave/">Dave
Thomas</a> and <a href="http://www.chadfowler.com/">Chad
Fowler</a>, two elite Ruby programmers (and
excellent teachers). While I wouldn't consider every topic covered
during the course advanced, I will say that there was a good mix of
intermediate and advanced content (and some of the advanced stuff was
really advanced!)</p>

<p><strong>Day 1</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Blocks, Procs, and Closures</li>
<li>Ruby Internals</li>
<li>Your Own Private Ruby</li>
<li>Design in a Dynamic Language</li>
<li>Types</li>
<li>Performance</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Day 2</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Metaprogramming</li>
<li>Creating Domain Specific Languages</li>
<li>Exotic Control Flow</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Day 3</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Library Organization</li>
<li>Distributed Programming</li>
<li>Debugging and Profiling</li>
<li>Ruby Extras</li>
</ul>


<p>The first day we jumped right into blocks, procs, and closures. At
first, I thought this would be primarily review for me, but Dave and
Chad always provide those few extra tidbits which make it interesting.
From there we delved into the Ruby source code and learned how to
construct Ruby classes in C code and how to find our way around the Ruby
source. "Your Own Private Ruby" covered how to build Ruby (with specific
extensions) and how to manage multiple copies of Ruby on the same
machine. There were so many goodies in the "Design in a Dynamic
Language" portion of the day, I don't want to ruin the experience for
those who haven't attended yet. The second day of the studio was my
favorite, covering metaprogramming, DSLs, and control flow. There was so
much material that it's hard to do it justice in a short blog posting.
The exercises/labs were integral to understanding the material and I'm
glad the slides and source code were provided as they've turned out to
be useful references to refer back to. The third day was the 'choose
your own adventure' day where each of us voted on the topics for the
day. Even though there seemed to be some interest in JRuby on the first
day, that topic didn't make the short list for the final day.
Concurrency also fell by the way-side (though the slides provided
contained more than enough material on Ruby threads). Distributed
programming was largely review for me having played with DRb and the
Rinda tuple space, though the discussion of multicast and the ease of
dealing with binary protocol using pack/unpack was new and useful to me.
The primary message regarding library organization is to follow the
conventions set forth by Rails, though this was the portion of the class
where we packaged our own gem and served it up to classmates. Debugging
and profiling Ruby applications was partially review, having used
benchmark, ruby-debug, and profiler. Yet, I had never thought to debug
my Ruby applications using gdb even though I use it frequently at work
to debug C/C++ applications. <a href="http://clarkware.com/cgi/blosxom">Mike</a>
and Nicole Clark really brought everything together. Their stewardship
of the event made it truly remarkable (as they seem to do every time).
Their goal is to ensure that every single attendee has a wonderful time
and they appear to be willing to do whatever it takes to make it so.
Next time you're at one of their events be sure to thank them for their
diligence. Overall, I found the course to be of tremendous value as it
got me thinking about even more ways to use Ruby. The insight that Chad
and Dave provided was integral to unlocking the reasoning behind the
design of the language. As is true with all of the <a href="http://pragmaticstudio.com/">Pragmatic
Studio</a> offerings I've attended, this class
reinvigorated me and left me energized to tackle more projects. For
those who have never been to a Pragmatic Studio event before, one of the
best alumni benefits is the mailing list you're able to join afterwards
-- the signal to noise ratio is extremely high. Now, if only I could
convince my employer to send me four or five times a year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rails Edge Day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-04T17:44:42-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By the final day of the conference my head was about to explode with the
amount of new information crammed into it. There were some great tips
and tricks on the final day, but overall, I think the conference peaked
on day two. Here's a run down of the sessions for day three:</p>

<ul>
<li>Buried Treasure: Hidden Rails Tips by Dave Thomas</li>
<li>The Streamlined Framework by Justin Gehtland</li>
<li>Rinda and DRb by Justin Gehtland</li>
<li><ul>
<li>Amazon's S3 Web Services by Marcel Molina, Jr.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Rake: Building Up Ruby by Jim Wierich</li>
<li>Rails Production Tips and Tricks by James Duncan Davidson</li>
</ul>


<p>Dave Thomas started out the day with a collection of Rails (and Ruby)
tips and tricks that he's acquired. He gave an overview of with_scope
which sets default params for ActiveRecord methods. Next were named
routes with_options and the fact that with_options works with any
method that takes a hash (such as table creation in migrations). The
returning ... do ... end block format which saves you from having to
explicitly return your object after doing some other work first. The
ampersand-colon trick which Dave calls the Blockinator:</p>

<p><del> {lang="ruby"}
%w{ cat dog }.map(&amp;:upcase)
</del></p>

<p>The date and time goodies added by Rails were discussed next (such as
the various to_s versions, like :db, :short, :long and ActiveSupport's
DATE_FORMATS hash which you can add your own formats to in
environment.rb). Enumerable extensions such as group_by, index_by and
sum. Array extensions like in_groups_of and to_sentence. String
extensions like at, from, to, first, last and each_char. Subversion
integration in the Rails scripts (--svn option to generate/destroy).
Using your app via the console, reload! in the console, setting a
default object in irb. And several useful TextMate tricks. Next up was
Justin with his talk about Streamlined.
<a href="http://www.streamlinedframework.org/">Streamlined</a> is a pretty nice
framework for building the back-end of your Rails app (or for an
enterprise web app, possibly the front-end as well). But, frankly, I'm
sick and tired of hearing about it. I've attended at least four
different events where either Stu or Justin presented Streamlined. After
a short break, Justin came back and spoke about Rinda and DRb. Since I'd
attended <a href="http://www.bosatsu.net/">Brian Sletten</a>'s NoVA RUG
presentation this was all review for me. The ideas behind Rinda and DRb
are very interesting and I would encourage you to read up on them. Next
Marcel gave an overview of his <a href="http://amazon.rubyforge.org">AWS::S3
library</a> which makes it very easy to use
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/S3-AWS-home-page-Money/b/ref=sc_fe_l_2/102-1786598-6301708?ie=UTF8&amp;node=16427261&amp;no=3435361&amp;me=A36L942TSJ2AJA">Amazon's
S3</a>
service from your Ruby programs and it even comes with an interactive
shell for working with S3. Following lunch Jim gave an excellent
presentation on Rake and showed how to create a task for generating
graphs in PNG format from digraph models. He started off with a very
simple example and then refactored it to use the various features of
Rake such as dependencies, file tasks, file lists, dynamic tasks, the
CLEAN and CLOBBER lists, rules, pathmapping, library tasks, and finally,
incorporating your own Rake tasks into your Rails projects. The final
presentation of the conference discussed production tips and tricks by
Duncan. He attempted to answer the most common questions regarding going
into production such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>How much hardware do I really need? Two to four machines for
redundancy: primary and backup web servers and primary and backup
database servers.</li>
<li>How many Mongrel instances should I fire up? Two to four instances
on a dual core machine, the rule of thumb is # of CPU's * 2.</li>
<li>What should I do with my logfiles? Logfiles are gold for root cause
analysis, you should aggregate logs onto a single machine, you may
wish to use something like the FiveRuns solution or syslog over the
network and ensure that you always filter out sensitive data.</li>
<li>What kind of load balancer should I use? You could try round-robin
DNS, but Pound/Pen software load balancers are quite good. A
hardware load balancer is fine if you have the money but is
overkill.</li>
<li>Should I use Amazon's EC2? Consider it, but keep an eye on it.</li>
<li>How often should I deploy? Often.</li>
<li>Should I deploy into production with edge Rails? You can, there are
many others that do it, but be prepared for issues. Unless you're
really comfortable with it, just use Rails 1.2 for now.</li>
<li>How do I test with real-world data? Get your production data back to
the development team.</li>
</ul>


<p>Overall, I thought this small regional conference was defintely worth
it. Especially since I spent my own money to attend (unfortunely I don't
get to work on Rails at my day job). The single track was great for
keeping everyone on the same page and fostering great inter-session
discussion. If the Rails Edge is headed your way, I would definitely
encourage you to attend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rails Edge Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-04T16:59:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The second day of the conference was even better than the first, in my
opinion. There were several more talks which I was eager to hear. Here's
an overview of the second day's presentations:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creating Rails Plugins by Chad Fowler and Bruce Williams</li>
<li>The Presenter Pattern by Marcel Molina, Jr.</li>
<li>The Deployment Golden Path by James Duncan Davidson</li>
<li>Testing Rails Apps by Stu Halloway</li>
<li>Red, Green, Refactor by Jim Weirich</li>
<li>Building View Frameworks by Bruce Williams</li>
<li>Lightning Talks</li>
</ul>


<p>Read on for my notes. First up were Chad and Bruce who went through
Creating Rails Plugins. Never having created a Rails plugin before, I
was very interested in the process. They started by providing an
overview of the plugin script and then the generate plugin script. Next
they showed how you can provide your own controllers (in the lib subdir)
and views (in the views/'plugin name' subdir), rake tasks (in the tasks
subdir), models (right at the top-level of your plugin) and your own
generators (in the generators/'plugin name' subdir). The remainder of
the talk walked through the creation of their
<a href="http://rubyforge.org/projects/ratable/">acts_as_ratable</a> plugin.
Marcel followed that with his talk on the Presenter Pattern. He was
quick to point out that this is not a design pattern in the style of the
Gang-of-Four book (especially since previous presenters had made
derogatory comments about design patterns and their utility). The
presenter pattern is basically a way to <em>organize</em> a chunk of view code.
He started off with a discussion of the problems with helper modules,
how they become a dumping ground for methods (one suggestion was to
break-up your helpers into smaller modules organized around specific
functionality and then include those in your helper). A comparison was
made to the 'method object' in Kent Beck's Smalltalk Best Practice
Patterns (linked at bottom of this post). To finish, Marcel gave a brief
demo of this but it's basically vaporware at this point and didn't have
a date for when it would be released. JDD was up next with his talk on
Deployment. He stressed that it was important to start deploying your
app as soon as possible in the development cycle (he suggested that you
do it at the same time you set up your Subversion repository). This is
necessary to find all of the "interesting" deployment problems up front,
so you can get into the deployment rhythm and so that you can show
others what you're working on for feedback. You just need a machine that
works well enough, he suggested a Mac mini, but some folks in the
audience suggested a virtual machine on the same box -- Duncan said that
while that might work he prefers having another machine to deploy to.
The only deployment solution that he recommends right now is Mongrel
fronted by Apache, Lighty, Pound, Pen or a hardware load balancer. Then
he went on to describe what he calls 'the golden path' using Capistrano,
Subversion and Unix machines. At the end he gave a live demo deploying
his app to an Amazon EC2 machine. After lunch, Stu presented on Testing
Rails Apps. Perhaps I'm insecure about my testing and test coverage
(though Mike Clark's rcov Rake task certainly provides peace-of-mind),
but I always find myself very interested in the testing methodologies of
others. Stu started off by discussion the reasons to write tests (tight
feedback loop, easy refactoring, early warning, cheap measure of success
and that it makes bad code painful). He went through testing models
(ensure your tests are self-documenting, test everything in sight and
then evolve your own style), fixtures (YAML, always use valid data, use
ERB for dynamic data), controllers (check out the scaffold: it tests
responses, redirects, model updates and uses restful verbs), managing
your tests (group and run using rake, manage your fixtures with rake,
put your common tasks in test_helper.rb). He then went through an
example of testing a space station w/o having access to a rocket, so he
used flexmock to mock one up, like this:</p>

<p>~~~~ {lang="ruby"}
def test_refuel_with_mock_recorder
  rocket = flexmock("rocket")
  rocket.should_expect do |rec|</p>

<pre><code>rec.dock.ordered
rec.attach_fuel_hose.ordered
rec.add_fuel(Integer).returns(50).ordered
rec.detach_fuel_hose.ordered
rec.undock.ordered
</code></pre>

<p>  end
  @station.refuel(rocket, 50)
  assert_equal 950, @station.fuel
end
~~~~</p>

<p>He then went on to recommend rcov and said that you should have 100% of
your code covered. He ran out of time before he could cover the
<a href="http://www.degrunt.net/articles/2006/08/27/cerberus-continious-integration-for-rails/">Cerberus</a>
continuous integration tool. Jim Weirich sat down for a live coding
presentation entitled, "Red, Green, Refactor" in which he demonstrated
test/behavior driven development. The steps were:</p>

<ol>
<li>Write a new test and watch it fail</li>
<li>Write just enough code for the test to pass</li>
<li>remove duplication, clean up, etc. and repeat</li>
</ol>


<p>He spoke in terms of dividing your perspective into two parts a Dr.
Jekyll who writes a test that forces you to write the code you need and
a Mr. Hyde who deliberately writes the minimal amount of code that
passes the tests. His demo seemed pedantic at first, but because you
have this extremely lazy Mr. Hyde you really have to think about your
tests and write them such that you force the implementation to be
correct. Bruce Williams spoke about Building View Frameworks and made
the example code available at his
<a href="http://codefluency.com/examples/ui_frameworks.tar.gz">site</a>. I was
really looking forward to this talk and Bruce didn't disappoint. He
started off discussion the traditional methods of DRYing up your views:
Helpers, Block Helpers and Partials then he went into REST DRYing with
the simply_helpful plugin. Next he went into some new territory for me,
DRY interactions by creating a controller DSL, controller plugins and
"big frameworks" as he called them. He gave examples of this from his
work at Naviance: folder_for (which created a tabbed view for the
different folders), paginated_index which was a controller DSL,
roster_for (which was very similar to paginated_index) and a calendar
which was a controller plugin. Bruce suggested using plugins and writing
your own and contributing them back to the community as well as testing
your views with Watir or Selenium. Following the presentations, were the
lightning talks. I was unable to stay for all of them but some of the
more notable ones were: Aaron from <a href="https://www.revolutionhealth.com/preview?code=gJ3AyxODNg">Revolution
Health</a>
demo'ed their huge web app (or more accurately collection of integrated
web apps) and spoke about their PluGems solution which has been document
on their <a href="http://revolutiononrails.blogspot.com/">blog</a>. It looks like
they're really doing some interesting work and having a lot of fun doing
it (plus I'm jealous of their development environment -- I wish my
employer gave each of us MacBook Pros instead of Lenovo ThinkPads); Next
<a href="http://jaredrichardson.net/">Jared Richardon</a>, author of <a href="http://www.pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/prj/">Ship
It</a>, spoke about his
consulting work on a new search engine site called
<a href="http://www.chacha.com/">ChaCha</a> and how they scaled Rails by removing
ActiveRecord in production. They use Rails as normal during development
and then extract out all of the SQL queries and tune them for
production; <a href="http://mcornick.org/">Mark Cornick</a> gave a quick run-down
on the service manager framework in Solaris and <a href="http://mcornick.org/stories/91-mongrel-meet-smf-smf-meet-mongrel">how he used it to
launch his Rails app when the machine
boots</a>.
Since we use a fair amount of Solaris at work and I'm not that familiar
with this feature, I found his talk quite enlightening. The presenters
have really been pimping Kent Beck's book, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Smalltalk-Best-Practice-Patterns-Kent/dp/013476904X/ref=sr_1_1/102-1786598-6301708?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1173043516&amp;sr=1-1">Smalltalk Best Practice
Patterns</a>
-- so of course, I picked up a copy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Rails Edge Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2007-03-04T16:02:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2007/03/04/the-rails-edge-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.pragmaticstudio.com/therailsedge/index.html"><img src="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/railsedgewhite.jpg" alt="image" /></a></p>

<p>Recently, I attended <a href="http://www.pragmaticstudio.com/therailsedge/index.html">The Rails
Edge</a> conference
run by <a href="http://www.pragmaticstudio.com/">The Pragmatic Studio</a>. It was a
single track event with some of the best and brightest folks in the
Rails and Ruby community. The speaker line-up was as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://pragdave.pragprog.com/pragdave/">Dave Thomas</a></li>
<li><a href="http://clarkware.com/cgi/blosxom">Mike Clark</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.duncandavidson.com/">James Duncan Davidson</a></li>
<li><a href="http://chadfowler.com/">Chad Fowler</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.relevancellc.com/">Justin Gehtland</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.relevancellc.com/">Stuart Halloway</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.vernix.org/marcel/">Marcel Molina, Jr.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.onestepback.org/">Jim Weirich</a></li>
<li><a href="http://codefluency.com/">Bruce Williams</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Read on for a description of the first day's sessions. After a brief
welcome from Mike Clark, Dave Thomas launched the conference with his
first session entitled "Metaprogramming Ruby: Extending Ruby for Fun and
Profit." He showed how classes were open by re-opening the String class
and adding a method to encrypt the contents of the string and then he
reimplemented the Rails modifications to Fixnum (so that
3.days.from_now works). He showed how code could be executed in the
context of a class as that class was loaded (i.e. we could conditionally
include/exclude methods in the class). Adding <em>macros</em> to Rails
controllers was achieved using the <strong>Module.included</strong> method to detect
when the Module was included in a controller and then perform some
actions on that controller (such as adding methods to it). Next the
power of <strong>eval</strong> and <strong>instance_eval</strong> was displayed--though he
cautioned that eval'ing user input could be very dangerous. Finally, he
showed how <strong>define_method</strong> could be used to create new methods on a
controller like so:</p>

<p>~~~~ {lang="ruby"}
class ApplicationController &lt; ActionController::Base
  def self.search_action_for(table_name)</p>

<pre><code>model = table_name.to_s.classify.constantize
define_method("search_for_#{table_name}") do
  @title = "Your #{Inflector.humanize(table_name)}"
  @results = model.find(:all, :conditions =&gt; ["name like ?", "%#{params[:term]}%"])
  render :template =&gt; '/shared/search_results'
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end
~~~~</p>

<p>and you would use it like this:</p>

<p><del> {lang="ruby"}
class UsersController &lt; ApplicationController
  search_action_for :users
end
</del></p>

<p>Following a short break, Mike Clark gave an overview of what's new in
Rails 1.2. Mike started off by listing the various virtual machines that
are under development for Ruby, such as
<a href="http://www.atdot.net/yarv/">YARV</a>,
<a href="http://jruby.codehaus.org/Home">JRuby</a>,
<a href="http://blog.fallingsnow.net/rubinius/">Rubinius</a>,
<a href="http://www.rubyclr.com/">RubyCLR</a>,
<a href="http://cardinal2.rubyforge.org/">Cardinal</a>, and
<a href="http://smallthought.com/avi/?p=19">smalltalk.rb</a>. Then he went on to
discuss migrations, plugins, rich models, parameter filtering,
deprecations, integration test (a testing DSL), running Rails in
headless mode (via the console), form_for, RJS, serialization,
respond_to, named routes, CRUD/REST, syndication, ActiveResource,
Mongrel, Capistrano, full-featured scaffold, Amazon S3, and Rinda/DRB.
Next Stu gave his talk on Ruby Idioms for Rails Programmers. He covered
the explicit API (which was Java code) and the implict API of today and
how the implict API is implemented as many small modules included into
big classes. Personalized Object Models (POM) were next, this is done by
augmenting other people's code, implementing DSLs with method-on-demand,
using method_missing sparingly, and being domain specific. His
presentation is available at <a href="http://www.codecite.com">CodeCite</a>. Chad
was up next with his talk on The Meaning of CRUD. This presentation went
into the meaning of CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Destroy), RESTful routes
and the SimplyHelpful plugin. This topic has been discussed at length
elsewhere so I won't go into the details. But Chad is always a great
speaker and I enjoyed his presentation immensely. Following lunch there
was a switch to the schedule as Jim Weirich hadn't arrived yet. So
Justin stepped up and gave his talk on Rails and Ajax. This presentation
is also available online at <a href="http://www.codecite.com">CodeCite</a>. Justin
started off with a discussion of the
<a href="http://www.prototypejs.org/">Prototype</a> JavaScript library with some
simple examples, then launched into the various effects possible with
<a href="http://script.aculo.us/">Script.aculo.us</a>. To wrap up, RJS was
described along with JSON. This led nicely into Marcel's talk on Reusing
RJS. He started off by showing some duplicated RJS code into two actions
within the same controller. For the first pass he tried extracting out a
new private method with the duplicate code, but unfortunately it didn't
work since it was in the wrong scope. So he extracted it out to a helper
and ensured that it could be passed the page object. This worked, but
calling the new method looked really ugly (Marcel called this Pythonic).
His next approach was to monkey patch JavaScriptGenerator right in Rails
-- invoking the new methods looked great, but he decided it wasn't worth
it to abuse method_missing plus it became a maintenance headache. So
Marcel went back to the origins of RJS and explained some of the design
choices that he and Sam made and reminded us that &lt;&lt; just adds raw
JavaScript to the stream. So he decided just to wrap update_page in the
helper and then reuse the code with &lt;&lt; like so:</p>

<p>~~~~ {lang="ruby"}
module ArticlesHelper
  def replace_article(article)</p>

<pre><code>update_page do |page|
  page[article].replace :partial =&gt; article
  page.replace_html :controls, :partial =&gt; 'shared/controls'
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
~~~~</p>

<p>and then he reused it:</p>

<p>~~~~ {lang="ruby"}
  def show</p>

<pre><code>render :update do |page|
  page &lt;&lt; replace_article(@article)
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
  def update</p>

<pre><code>@article.update_attributes(params[:article])
render :update do |page|
  page &lt;&lt; replace_article(@article)
  page.visual_effect :highlight, dom_id(@article)
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
~~~~</p>

<p>The great thing about this is that you can also reuse that JavaScript in
your views as well:</p>

<p><del> {lang="html"}
Edit Article
&lt;% article_form(article) do |form| %>
  &lt;%= render :partial => 'articles/form', : object => form %>
  &lt;%= submit_tag 'Save changes' %> or
  &lt;%= link_to_function 'Cancel', replace_article(article) %>
&lt;% end %>
</del></p>

<p>After a short break, several conference attendees came up and demo'ed
their apps. Some of the presenters were: <a href="http://www.ehatchersolutions.com/">Erik
Hatcher</a> who presented on his Solr.rb
project (the acts_as_solr.rb plugin) and his work at UVA categorizing
literature; <a href="http://rgarver.blogspot.com/">Ryan Garver</a> spoke about the
<a href="http://info.aws-console.com/">AWS Console</a> which makes it really easy
to setup your server on Amazon Web Services EC2; <a href="http://www.metaskills.net/blog/colophon/who-is-to-blame-for-this">Ken
Collins</a>
spoke about <a href="http://www.homemarks.com/">Homemarks</a>, simple project-based
bookmarking, which he is open sourcing; Finally, someone from the
<a href="http://fiveruns.com">FiveRuns</a> team demo'ed their hosted systems
management solution. While it certainly looks nice, I know my employer
would never use it as it requires installing their software on your
systems so it can report back to them. After dinner, Dave Thomas gave
the opening keynote, entitled Fear of Flying. It was very good and I
believe it was the same as the EuroRailsConf keynote that he gave, which
is available
<a href="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-7327520943909344563">online</a>.
Overall, the first day of The Rails Edge went very well and got me
re-energized to work on my projects with several new ideas and a fresh
perspective. I don't think you can put a price on that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails Studio Reston]]></title>
    <link href="http://sean.github.com/blog/2005/11/24/rails-studio-reston/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-24T08:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sean.github.com/blog/2005/11/24/rails-studio-reston</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday and Saturday, I attended the very first <a href="http://studio.pragprog.com/">Pragmatic Rails
Studio</a> in Reston, VA. I highly recommend
attending the studio to anyone interested in
<a href="http://www.rubyonrails.org">Rails</a> development. Unfortunately, I wasn't
able to take more time off from work and attend the Thursday session on
Ruby (though I already know enough <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org">Ruby</a> to
be dangerous). Dave and Mike really know their stuff and have "real
world" examples of what was easy and where they ran into pitfalls in
Rails. And Nicole took care of all of the little details which make a
training session great (Thanks!)</p>

<h3>Day 1</h3>

<p>The pace of the first day was a bit slow for me as I'd already been
playing around with Rails for a couple months and had written some small
web-apps. But David and Mike had to lay the ground-work so that everyone
was on the same page. Thankfully, for those of us who had already worked
our way through <a href="http://www.pragmaticprogrammer.com/titles/rails/index.html">Agile Web Development with
Rails</a>, they
had updated the Depot application with some added features (such as
Ajax, email, migrations, additional testing, etc). After getting the
basics out of the way they went into detail about
<a href="http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/pages/UnderstandingMigrations">migrations</a>
-- I had heard about migrations at OSCON from Lucas Carlson and John
Butler, but at the time I didn't bother investigating since it didn't
sound that useful to me -- boy, was I wrong. Since learning migrations,
I haven't written another bit of SQL DDL -- and I love it! After that
they spoke a bit about scaffolding and models and then demo'ed
<a href="http://www.robbyonrails.com/articles/2005/08/18/are-you-a-console-master">script/console</a>
(basically irb with Rails loaded inside of it). Using the console, they
showed how to debug your app, fix issues in the DB and simply browse the
DB -- after the training, the console became a bigger part of my
development style and now I test things out before 'coding and
reloading'. After that we discussed model validation, the find method
(and how the find_by_ methods are dynamically generated), SQL
injection, rendering, testing and avoiding GETs with side-effects -- all
of this was review for me, but it had to be covered. Dave showed off
some debugging techniques, where the logs were and that many issues can
be resolved by removing or resetting the session. Finally, Dave and Mike
added some Ajax to the Depot 2.0 app to update the cart in the sidebar
without reloading the page and then added the yellow-fade technique so
that the user's attention is drawn to the cart change. There was one
significant issue during the training which affected many folks:
rendering the cart in the sidebar caused an infinite rendering loop so
the page would load completely blank and there was no information about
a stack overflow in the logs. So if you find that you've added a render
call and now the page is completely blank you might have this problem be
sure that the render command has set layout to false.</p>

<h3>Day 2</h3>

<p>Dave and Mike decided to change the pace so that instead of everyone
following along coding, our job was to watch, listen and ask questions.
This allowed us to cover ground much more quickly. First we discussed
web forms and the two different ways in which they could be implemented
with Rails: the two action update (two different methods in the
controller are used, the scaffold works this way with edit and update)
and the one action update (a single method in the controller handles
both the GET request and the POST request). They said which one you
choose depends on your circumstances, but with tools like <a href="http://www.37signals.com/svn/archives2/google_web_accelerator_hey_not_so_fast_an_alert_for_web_app_designers.php">Google Web
Accelerator</a>
it might not be so bad for your actions to prevent GET requests from
updating the application state. Then we talked about has_many and
belongs_to and managing complex hierarchies (such as many-to-many
associations and the acts_as tools). Since I had not messed with HABTM
or the acts_as stuff, I found this interesting and am looking for ways
to apply it in my next project. Following this Mike explained
ActionMailer: how to configure Rails for sending and receiving email,
how to generate a mailer and render it. Then we moved on to testing.
First, functional testing (i.e. controller testing) was covered along
with common assertions and the test environment, then we spoke about
fixtures and how to embed Ruby code in them for generating many records,
we discussed mock objects briefly and there was some discussion
regarding how these mocks differ from Java's mocks. Dave then talked
about partial templates and their usefulness when rendering collections.
A brief overview of the flash was next. Hooks, both in ActiveRecord and
ActionController, were explained. Since I had never used the hooks in
ActiveRecord, I found this discussion interesting while the overview of
filters in ActionController was all review. The ActiveRecord hooks seem
great for debugging, though I think they would slow down the application
quite a bit if you took advantage of every single one -- I guess if you
need to massage the data going into/coming out of the DB then hooks
could really be useful. Next routes were covered as an intro to web
services. I had played around with routes briefly and found them to be
really powerful. The overview of webservices was quick -- I had already
written a RESTful one and would be perfectly happy to spend the rest of
my life without ever having to write a SOAP/XML-RPC web service, so I
didn't object. Mike then spoke about his experience working on
VitalSource and how important interface design is for your web-app. He
also urged everyone to get the web designer involved as early as
possible in the project. He stressed the importance of creating many
helpers to extract out the view for components. He recommended waiting
to add Ajax until the end of the project and that it is better to use it
subtly than to over do it. Following that we spoke more about SQL
injection, CSS/XSS, not to trust parameters (especially the id),
validate and sanitize uploaded files, don't cache authenticated pages,
use functional tests to seal potential holes (and recommended checking
out <a href="http://www.owasp.org">OWASP</a>). Deployment was next. First Mike
discussed the architecture of your web-app (share nothing!) and that you
should move to saving sessions in the DB since multiple instances of
your app will be running on different servers. As far as the webserver,
Dave and Mike were split on Apache and Lighty, respectively (Dave
doesn't think Lighty is quite there yet in terms of rock solid stability
and Mike hasn't had any issues with Lighty -- he admits his Apache-fu is
not that great). Mike talked about setting up your application to email
you (or your cell phone) when things go wrong and Dave discussed the
logs some more (and mentioned
<a href="http://rails-analyzer.rubyforge.org">SyslogLogger</a>). Some techniques
for optimizing your app were discussed (such as preloading child rows,
using find_by_sql, etc) and caching. Page caching was discussed first,
followed by action caching and fragement caching -- I had never used
these techniques, but they seem straight-forward enough -- Dave
cautioned that caching only works in production mode, so if you enable
caching and don't see it working check that first. To end the studio,
Mike gave a great demonstration of
<a href="http://weblog.rubyonrails.com/articles/2005/10/19/introducing-switchtower-distributed-deployment-for-rails">SwitchTower</a>
which showed how easy it is to deploy your app (whether you deploy to a
single machine or a cluster) and how easy it is to rollback if you found
an issue after deployment. Dave and Mike reminded us to roll our log
files (I think there was an issue on
<a href="http://www.textdrive.com">TextDrive</a> where someone's exceeded their
quota by far with huge log files), purge old sessions and schedule daily
maintenance with cron.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
