<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Telecom | Sean Mountcastle]]></title>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/categories/telecom/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-01T22:18:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Mountcastle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smountcastle@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally Awarded a Patent!]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/12/27/finally-awarded-a-patent/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-27T10:32:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/12/27/finally-awarded-a-patent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After almost seven years, I was finally awarded a patent:
<a href="http://patft.uspto.gov/netacgi/nph-Parser?Sect1=PTO1&amp;Sect2=HITOFF&amp;d=PALL&amp;p=1&amp;u=/netahtml/PTO/srchnum.htm&amp;r=1&amp;f=G&amp;l=50&amp;s1=7,170,862.PN.&amp;OS=PN/7,170,862&amp;RS=PN/7,170,862" title="Partitioning a network element into multiple virtual network elements"><strong>7,170,862</strong></a>.
It&rsquo;s assigned to my previous employer, <a href="http://cisco.com/">Cisco Systems,
Inc</a>. Until I started this process, I never imagined
how long the <a href="http://www.uspto.gov/index.html">USP&amp;TO</a> could take to
finally assign a patent. Now I&rsquo;m waiting to see if any of my other
patents filed by Cisco will be awarded.</p>

<p>This actually happened back in January, but since I was never notified,
I researched it myself after the recent news of Cisco opening up IOS to
3rd party developers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AT&T Insanity]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/14/att-insanity/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-14T15:18:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/14/att-insanity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friend <a href="http://blacka.com/david/">Dave</a> <del>is</del> was looking to get an
<a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/">iPhone</a> now that his <a href="http://blacka.com/david/archives/2007/07/the-irony/">Treo
died</a>. I already
have AT&amp;T service and I&rsquo;d love to upgrade to an iPhone as well. Being an
old AT&amp;T Wireless customer from before they were purchased by Cingular
and renamed (and now back to the old name) does not appear to be an
asset. I&rsquo;ve had the service before I was married, consequently if I&rsquo;m
going to upgrade my phone, consolidating my service with my wife&rsquo;s
through <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/easysetup/rateplans.html">AT&amp;T&rsquo;s family
plan</a> would
probably be best for us. Thus I called up AT&amp;T to see if they could
assist me. Unfortunately, my service is through the national business
accounts arm of the company and the family plan is not an option there.
I have no problem being switched off of the national business accounts
(and forgoing my monthly discount), but their system won&rsquo;t let them
convert my account. I can leave AT&amp;T and go to another service provider,
taking my number with me but I cannot stay with AT&amp;T and switch to the
family plan. If I leave to go to another carrier, taking my number with
me, and then go back to AT&amp;T, I&rsquo;ll still be stuck on the national
business accounts side of the house. The service representative said she
could set me up with a completely new account (i.e. new phone numbers)
with the family plan. I explained that I&rsquo;ve had my cell number for a
decade now and I&rsquo;m not going to change it. I&rsquo;m willing to pay them more
money (almost double what I pay now) and purchase one (possibly even
two) expensive handsets and they cannot help me out at all. This is
completely insane! AT&amp;T really needs to get its act together and
integrate its back office systems.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodbye Cisco]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/10/30/goodbye-cisco/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-30T21:19:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/10/30/goodbye-cisco</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My previous employer, <a href="http://www.cisco.com">Cisco Systems</a>, has decided
to restructure my business unit and as a result my choices were to
either move or leave and since my family is quite happy in Northern
Virginia, I decided to find employment elsewhere. The restructuring was
necessary for Cisco, and personally I thought they should&rsquo;ve taken
action much sooner than they did. The company made a series of bad
business decisions in the optical business, not the least of which was
paying $6.9 billion for the start-up at which I worked. The world is
moving to ethernet and IP and the focus should&rsquo;ve been on leveraging the
team&rsquo;s existing experience in telecom (and SONET/SDH, in particular) to
move to an IP-based platform. I was eager to see Cisco&rsquo;s shift its image
to a consumer-focused company&mdash;even though I think the new logo looks
considerably worse than the old one. Even though I&rsquo;m planning to get rid
of my cable service in favor of FiOS TV, it would&rsquo;ve been nice to see
the Cisco enhancements to the SciAtl set-top boxes. And as a Cisco
share-holder, the fact that consumer companies seem to have higher
multiples has given the stock a nice little rise since early August.
I&rsquo;ll continue to keep my eye on Cisco and now that I&rsquo;m no longer an
employee I can blog about them much more freely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSCON: Asterisk Inside and Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/07/24/oscon-asterisk-inside-and-out/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-24T21:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/07/24/oscon-asterisk-inside-and-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I attended <a href="http://conferences.oreillynet.com/cs/os2006/view/e_sess/8936">Asterisk Inside and
Out</a> by
<a href="http://www.saintjoe.edu/faculty/specific/cs.html">Brian Capouch</a>. His
presentation is available
<a href="http://www.network-voice.com/oscon/tutorial.pdf">here</a> while all of the
<a href="http://www.asterisk.org/">Asterisk</a> configuration files can be obtained
<a href="http://www.network-voice.com/oscon/">here</a>. The tutorial was based on
his forthcoming book, <em>Asterisk Inside and Out: Do-it-yourself Open
Source Telephony</em>, from Addison-Wesley.</p>

<p>Following the slides, Brian performed several demos which displayed the
power of Asterisk. He started with a simple ‘Hello World’ example where
the caller was played a short message. Next he demonstrated the server
calling you back (and playing a pre-recorded message). Then he called an
inside extension, an outside of the system (on to the PSTN via the FXO),
and called an inside extension from outside (via the PSTN and FXO).
After that he showed a ‘road warrior’ who ran a local instance of
Asterisk on their laptop which registered with the home office and then
called the office number of the ‘road warrior’ and the call was
automatically redirected to the laptop. Following that, he configured
the laptop as a remote office and dialed an extension at the ‘remote
office’ from the ‘local office’, which was properly routed through the
system. Finally, he demonstrated an intra-office transfer of an incoming
POTS call.</p>

<p>Asterisk appears to be an amazing application and there is quite a bit
more that I need to learn about it. It seems like it would be a fun
project to setup at home (if my wife will agree to it – which is
doubtful).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OSCON: JavaScript Boot Camp]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/07/24/oscon-javascript-boot-camp/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-24T20:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/07/24/oscon-javascript-boot-camp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I attended <a href="http://www.slash7.com/">Amy Hoy’s</a> <a href="http://conferences.oreillynet.com/cs/os2006/view/e_sess/8933">JavaScript
Boot Camp</a>
tutorial. The slides should be available online shortly at Amy’s website
– I’ll update this post once she publishes them. She provided a good
overview of JavaScript as a language, some of the issues with the
various implementations, how to debug it and some of the libraries
available for use. <strong>Updated</strong>: The slides are located
<a href="http://www.slash7.com/articles/2006/07/26/javascript-boot-camp-tutorial">here</a>.
Unfortunately, the material was a little too introductory for me, I
thought she’d spend less time on the JavaScript basics and more on the
intermediate/advanced techniques of the language and libraries. I guess
I misunderstood what I had signed-up for. Anyway, she started out with
the history of the JavaScript language (briefly mentioning the
LiveScript name … which Rich Kilmer quizzed me on at <a href="http://seanmountcastle.com/articles/2006/07/20/july-novarug-meeting">my RJS
talk</a>)
and the ECMAScript process which spawned several different releases of
JavaScript – basically most browsers implement JavaScript 1.5 with the
exception of <a href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/">Firefox</a> which gives us
JavaScript 1.6. At this point we lost power to everything but the
projector, but Amy took it in stride and continued her presentation. She
went through the syntax of the JavaScript language, keywords, etc. After
getting through the language quirks, she discussed how to use
<a href="http://www.joehewitt.com/software/firebug/">FireBug</a> and the
<a href="http://www.squarefree.com/shell/">JavaScript shell</a> to test and debug
your JavaScript code. Some of the libraries which were mentioned
include: <a href="http://www.json.org">JSON</a>, <a href="http://mochikit.com/">MochiKit</a>,
<a href="http://script.aculo.us/">Script.aculo.us</a>,
<a href="http://moofx.mad4milk.net/">moo.fx</a>,
<a href="http://bennolan.com/behaviour/">Behavior</a>, and
<a href="http://prototype.conio.net/">Prototype</a>. When asked for her favorite
JavaScript related sites she gave her top three:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.quirksmode.org/">QuirksMode</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mozilla.org/">Mozilla</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ajaxian.com/">Ajaxian</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
