<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Entertainment | Sean Mountcastle]]></title>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/categories/entertainment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-01T22:22:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sean Mountcastle]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[smountcastle@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. Horrible]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2008/07/18/dr-horrible/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-18T19:23:51-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2008/07/18/dr-horrible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NPR&rsquo;s <a href="http://wamu.org/programs/atc/">All Things Considered</a> had a <a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=92678153">nice
story</a> on
<a href="http://drhorrible.com/">Dr. Horrible</a> tonight. This enjoyable,
currently web-only, musical was produced during the writers' strike last
year by Joss Whedon. I highly recommend catching it while you still can.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Desire]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/08/on-desire/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-08T22:14:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/07/08/on-desire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/pbarnett.png" title="Paul Barnett"><img src="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/pbarnett.thumbnail.png" alt="Paul
Barnett" /></a></p>

<p>Last week, I was fortunate enough to be one of the few folks who
attended the <a href="http://games.groups.yahoo.com/group/igda_dc_chapter/">Northern
VA</a>
<a href="http://www.idga.org/cgi-bin/templates/single.html?topic=329">IGDA</a>
meeting where <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/behindTheScenes/meetTheTeam/paulBarnett.php">Paul
Barnett</a>
spoke to us about <em>desire</em>. Specifically what you can and cannot control
to influence your customers into buying your product (in his case a
subscription to a MMORPG). That is, to make them <em>desire</em> your product.
To warm up he spoke about the utility of mind maps and suggested reading
Tony Buzan&rsquo;s book on Mind Maps. While speaking about mind maps, he
hinted at the mind map he drew on the board in preparation for his talk.
As background, for those who may not know what <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/">Warhammer: Age of
Reckoning</a> (WAR) is, Paul explained
that it is <strong>not</strong> a computer game. As Paul sees it, computer games are
like &ldquo;washing powder&rdquo; (laundry detergent) in that it is a product which
is made, shipped and forgotten about. Next week there is always a better
version of washing powder on the market (new, improved, etc), to the
point where it seems like just weeks ago we were essentially washing our
clothes in dirt. WAR, in contrast, is a hobby game. As a hobby game it
requires skill, commitment and imagination. Hobbies are
self-obsessed/self-indulgent; a very personal endeavor. And WAR is not
just a game that is shipped and forgotten. Since it is a massively
multiplayer online game, the developers must constantly work to improve
the game while the customer service team resolves issues and others work
to lead in-game special events. EA Mythic is providing an experience
with WAR (as is Blizzard with World of Warcraft, aka WoW). Getting back
to the topic of the evening, Paul spoke of the three thwarts to your
product:</p>

<ol>
<li><strong>Acts of God</strong>. These are causes that you have no control over, so
you shouldn&rsquo;t try to overcome them. Examples included loss of
internet, loss of life, bankruptcy, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Your own fault</strong>. These are causes that you have total control
over which you can mitigate with planning, investment and training.
Examples included unstable code/servers, bad download experience,
bad customer service, bad install experience, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Not any good</strong>. These are causes that you have control over which
are extremely difficult to mitigate. You cannot just plan to have a
good game or invest in a good game. This is extremely subjective,
what one person thinks is great someone else may believe to be total
crap. Examples included balancing the game, making it engaging,
building a sense of community, etc.</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/board.jpg" title="board.jpg"><img src="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/board.thumbnail.jpg" alt="board.jpg" /></a></p>

<p>Once you&rsquo;ve built-up desire for your product you have to maintain it.
Paul stated that desire is eroded at audit points. Audit points are
times when the customer takes stock of their experience and consciously
chooses to continue paying you money or not. He compared audit points to
the form of interrogation where-by a person&rsquo;s head is held under water
for a period of time and then pulled out &mdash; those points when the person
comes up gasping for air are audit points. You have to keep people away
from audit points. Each of the thwarts mentioned above cause audit
points. Thus when you balance (or nerf) the game, you&rsquo;ve just changed
the user&rsquo;s experience and thus inserted an audit point. In addition,
when you release an expansion pack or a patch, it causes an audit point
as the user must choose whether or not to go out and purchase the
expansion pack which allows them access to new locations/adventures
taking them out of their comfort zone within the game. That&rsquo;s all well
and good, but how do you actually build desire for your product in the
first place? Paul believes that you must plan and invest in several
areas prior to the launch of your product. You should have transparent
communication from the very beginning (see <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/behindTheScenes/vidPhoneDiaries/index.php">Paul&rsquo;s video
blog</a>
along with <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/behindTheScenes/developmentDiaries/index.php">developer
interviews/podcasts</a>
and other behind the scenes material). You also need to build a sense of
community so that your customers and prospective customers feel part of
a greater whole. In this regard, EA Mythic has created <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/community/fansiteKit/">kits for fan
sites</a>,
<a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/community/forumsFansites/">forums</a>
on their website, special <a href="http://www.warhammeronline.com/english/community/eventsCalendar/">promotional
events</a>
and materials, etc. Another way to build desire is to ensure that your
product provides a sense of progression. This is very similar to the
notions espoused by <a href="http://headrush.typepad.com/creating_passionate_users/">Kathy
Sierra</a> around
helping your users kick ass. At the end of his talk, Paul mentioned the
&lsquo;innovator&rsquo;s dilemma&rsquo;, specifically evolution vs. revolution. He
estimated that new products can only support 2-3 innovations per
release, any more would simply overwhelm the market. For a product like
his, he gave examples like a unique HUD, unique control scheme,
completely different questing system, etc. In a related vein, he spoke
about &lsquo;crossing the chasm&rsquo;, loosely related to Geoffrey Moore&rsquo;s book
which discusses bridging the gap between the early adopters and the
early majority (the pragmatists). Paul&rsquo;s example was that of setting for
the game, fantsy vs. science fiction. His argument was that people can
relate to better to a fantasy world as everyone knows about cutting
enemies down with swords or clubbing them but shooting blaster cannons
or instaneous space travel, which don&rsquo;t exist in real life, take more of
a leap. Personally, I&rsquo;m not sure that&rsquo;s the reason why most Sci-Fi MMOs
are having a difficult time but he&rsquo;s certainly entitled to his opinion.
Overall, Paul&rsquo;s talk was quite enjoyable (in no small part to his
bitingly sarcastic British humor) and he has definitely made some
interesting observations, though it would seem that many are widely
known outside of the &ldquo;game development&rdquo; community. I look forward to
hearing more from Paul and the team at EA Mythic and will be keeping an
eye on the development of WAR.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Venture Bros.]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/02/20/the-venture-bros/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-20T20:58:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2007/02/20/the-venture-bros</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.adultswim.com/shows/venturebros/"><img src="http://seanmountcastle.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/02/venturebros.png" alt="image" /></a>
I&rsquo;ve been meaning to write about <a href="http://www.adultswim.com/shows/venturebros/">The Venture
Bros.</a> since I found out
about them over lunch during my interview at EA Mythic. I think that the
series is quite funny and have been enjoying it ever since I first heard
about it. Though I have seen reviews on the &lsquo;net which complain that the
show is infantile, others compare it to <em>South Park</em> and <em>The Simpsons</em>
as well as <em>Johnny Quest</em>. The last comparison is apt as that is where
Venture Brothers draws its inspiration, though all aspects of popular
culture are referenced in the shows. My personal favorite episode thus
far is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twenty_Years_to_Midnight">Twenty Years to
Midnight</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interviewing at EA Mythic]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/12/10/interviewing-at-ea-mythic/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-10T23:11:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/12/10/interviewing-at-ea-mythic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since I started playing video games at an early age, I always
wanted to develop them. I had my first taste of this in grade school
when I figured out how to modify some of my favorite games by editing
the data files in a hex editor. In high school, I bought myself a copy
of Borland Turbo Pascal (and then later Turbo C++) and taught myself how
to program&mdash;building rudimentary games. For college, my mother really
wanted me to become a lawyer so I decided that the best way to get there
was to major in political science. While I did well, I just wasn&rsquo;t
really interested in it. So in my junior year I changed my major to
computer science. Of course, I had already chosen my university based on
their reputation for political science and law and as such the computer
science curriculum wasn&rsquo;t the best. Since freshman year I had been
running a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MUD">MUD</a> (I had to finagle an
account on the engineering Ultrix machines as I wasn&rsquo;t in the School of
Engineering&mdash;we also weren&rsquo;t supposed to be running servers either but I
had some crafty ways to hide my work from the TAs). In my junior year I
built a raycasting engine and a simple FPS (similar to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolfenstein_3D">Wolfenstein
3D</a>). While I continued to
follow the game industry and read-up on the newest techniques from folks
like Michael Abrash, John Carmack, Andre LaMothe, etc. my foray into
game development was still-born. In my senior year I took an internship
at the Naval Research Lab and was pigeon-holed into telecommunications
from that point on (I believe I&rsquo;ve finally escaped, though I&rsquo;m currently
working on some very interesting and vital Internet infrastructure).
Anyway, you didn&rsquo;t come here to read about me and my failed attempts at
game development, you want to know about interviewing at EA&rsquo;s Mythic
Studio in Fairfax, VA. Home to Dark Age of Camelot (DAoC) and the
upcoming Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning (WAR). Back in July, I
contacted my friend Scott who works at <a href="http://www.bluefang.com/">Blue Fang
Games</a> in Waltham, MA to find out if he knew
anyone at <a href="http://www.mythicentertainment.com/">Mythic Entertainment</a>.
Fortunately he did, his friend Ralph, an artist at Mythic, was able to
put me in touch with the CTO, Matt. At this time they were still in
transition due to the acquisition of Mythic by Electronic Arts so Matt&rsquo;s
email address changed and communication was difficult. I continued to
persevere until Matt agreed to bring me in for an interview at the end
of August. It was an all day interview (from 10am until 5pm), which I
was glad for&mdash;I really dislike it when companies only speak to you for
an hour or two; it&rsquo;s just not enough time to assess someone. Knowing the
culture at the company I didn&rsquo;t wear a suit and tie to my interview, but
khaki pants and a button-down shirt thinking that I should at least
dress somewhat nicely to the interview (even this elicited a mixed
response, which I&rsquo;ll speak about later). When I arrived at Mythic, Matt
(the CTO) came out to greet me and spoke with me for a short while about
why I wanted to become a game developer, my professional experience and
skills. He then walked me over to speak with Darren who is essentially
the director of operations for Mythic, managing their datacenters and
ensuring that the hardware and network are operating. One of his direct
reports, Andrew, was in his office so they decided to tag-team interview
me&mdash;which I didn&rsquo;t mind. Darren explained his role, the machines in
their co-lo out in Ashburn and their pipe to the internet. Andrew
quizzed me about various programming languages and had me explain my
most recent project at Cisco. I brought up Ruby and tried to make a case
for it increasing their productivity in operations through the use of
scripts and custom web apps to help manage and monitor their systems.
Andrew was already using Python and had done some of this already
(though not to the extent I had envisioned) and didn&rsquo;t see the need to
learn yet another programming language. Granted Python and Ruby are
equivalent enough that one or the other is suitable for these type of
scripts/apps. Matt had thought that the best fit for me would be here in
the operations group since I did not have any professional game
development experience. Next I met with Ed who works on the WAR game
server. He explained that one of his biggest problems was NPC
path-finding and that they were evaluating a new library from a company
in Europe (France, I think). But even that wouldn&rsquo;t scale to the number
of NPCs they have in a shard. He showed me the &lsquo;tools&rsquo; they used to
design spells and NPC behavior&mdash;basically an Excel spreadsheet that the
game designers fill in that gets imported into the game server. I left
with some ideas on how to improve these tools quite a bit (using a DSL
written in Ruby that would be easy for the designers to write spells and
behaviors in or a Rails app which used Script.aculo.us for drag-and-drop
building of spells/NPC behavior from basic building blocks). Following
my meeting with Ed, the team took me out to lunch where I made a pretty
big mistake&mdash;instead of talking about games the whole time, I admitted
that I had to pack-up my PS2 over a year ago because my toddler kept
grabbing at the cords and opening the game cases. One good thing that
did come out of lunch is that I learned about <a href="http://www.adultswim.com/shows/venturebros/">The Venture
Bros.</a>, the best cartoon on
TV. I think it&rsquo;s absolutely hilarious and I&rsquo;ve been recommending it to
all of my friends ever since. When I got back to the office, they
introduced me to Brian who also worked on the WAR game server. I had a
great conversation with him and liked him quite a bit. He has been
working at Mythic (or Interworld Productions as it was known at the
time) since their first MUD, Dragon&rsquo;s Gate. What I found interesting
about Brian was that he had been working there since high school and had
no formal computer science background (though he said he was working on
his degree at GMU). An interesting tidbit that I learned from Brian is
that for all of the games Mythic has released, the server-side codebase
is derived from Dragon&rsquo;s Gate&mdash;they just keep adding functionality to it
over the years and try to patch over the brittle parts. After speaking
with both Ed and Brian, I was very excited about working on the WAR game
server and thought this was the group I could quickly contribute to.
Next they had me speak to another developer named Matt (not the CTO). At
first, I had mistakenly though he was in the operations group working
with Andrew and Darren. Matt works on the game server for DAoC which
appears to be in a sustaining mode. Following the interview, I was still
not clear on what work needed to be done on DAoC. I think this was one
of my worst interviews at the company as there seemed to be a lack of
understanding between us&mdash;the questions he was asking me were not at all
clear (perhaps that was the point), so I tried my best to tease more
information out of him and answer them to the best of my ability. As
sort of an afterthought they had me speak to Marty, another game server
developer on DAoC who said his background was on the client side (3D
Windows application programming). He was the most hostile towards me and
also the most frank. He was appalled by the fact that I had packed up my
PS2 to prevent my children from breaking it&mdash;he explained that if he
were in that position he would tell his wife to take the kids away so he
could play (the way he said this made me feel sorry for his family).
According to Marty they are only looking for folks who&rsquo;ve worked in the
game industry before or are hard-core gamers (at the expense of all
else, he recounted the personal sacrafices he made to get into
Mythic&mdash;essentially commuting up to Northern VA on Monday, staying for
the week and commuting back to his family for the weekend). His
rationale for preferring hard-core gamers was reasonable&mdash;he explained
that in design meetings they typically referred to other games and this
shared knowledge of the details of games (through having played them)
allowed the team to come to consensus much sooner. He used <a href="http://www.elderscrolls.com/games/oblivion_overview.htm">Elder
Scrolls
Oblivion</a> as an
example, but couldn&rsquo;t remember the name of the game (which I had to
remind him of). So while I stay up-to-date on the latest games, actually
having played them helps to build this shared gaming culture. Marty also
thought that I was way over-dressed for the interview (in khaki pants
and a button down shirt), he was wearing a t-shirt and shorts and I
thought I should&rsquo;ve worn something more casual. I tried to explain to
him that this was a job interview and that I wanted to make a good
impression but it had the reverse effect on him. Finally I had a sort of
exit interview with Matt (the CTO) who asked for my impression of the
team and the company (which was good) and he gave me a tour of the area
surrounding the art team for WAR. The art on the walls there is simply
amazing and having been a huge fan of Warhammer it was a real treat. At
this time he also explained to me why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mythic_Entertainment#Presently">Imperator
Online</a> was
cancelled&mdash;it just wasn&rsquo;t fun for them when they played through it.
MMO&rsquo;s with guns are really hard to balance and after many months of
development the game just wasn&rsquo;t coming together. Matt also confirmed
that WAR would be released on both the PC and the Xbox 360 (the latter
of which he recommended I get, instead of the PS3 or Wii). Matt was most
concerned about my salary at Cisco, constantly assuring me that they
would be unable to me it. I explained that I was willing to take a bit
of a pay cut for the opportunity to work as a game developer on
Warhammer. I left with mixed feelings, not sure whether I would be
offered a position at Mythic. I was quite surprised that I wasn&rsquo;t given
any form of coding test. Following Labor Day weekend, I heard back from
Matt that they decided not to offer me a position, here&rsquo;s the content of
his email:</p>

<blockquote><p>After a lot of consideration, we don&rsquo;t think it is a good fit for you
here at Mythic. You obviously are very talented at what you do, with
our limited position slots available here; we would like to fill them
with individuals with game job experience if possible. Take care, we
wish you the best with your future endeavors.</p></blockquote>

<p>Having gone through this experience and done quite a bit of research,
I&rsquo;ve come up with the following tips for interviewing at EA Mythic, or
any game developer:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you don&rsquo;t have any game industry experience, create your own by
making your own game. Go through the entire process and complete
it&mdash;don&rsquo;t show off a half finished game.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re not a rabid gamer, become one. At lunch talk about your
favorite games, why they are your favorites, what new games you&rsquo;re
looking forward to, etc. Here they&rsquo;re looking for passion. The
thought is if your passionate about games, your passion will show in
your work (and you&rsquo;ll be willing to work 80-100 hours during crunch
time, the two or so months prior to release).</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t try to push any new technology or programming language during
your interview. Once you&rsquo;ve gotten the job you can then try to
effect change. Instead show how your skills can work within the
existing situation to improve it. This is true of basically any
job&mdash;it&rsquo;s naive to think that you know better than they do after
having worked in the domain for so long. Though the game industry in
particular appears to be quite insular and has only recently started
switching to tools, processes and procedures that have been shown to
work well in software development projects.</li>
<li>Provide specific examples of how you can contribute to the team. You
need to sell yourself to them.</li>
<li>Research the company and culture as much as possible prior to the
interview. I did quite a bit of research about Mythic before
interviewing and knew a lot about the founders and the products, but
I didn&rsquo;t know that much about the culture. I should&rsquo;ve used Ralph
(my friend&rsquo;s friend) to find out more prior to my interview.</li>
<li>And, of course, they&rsquo;re looking to see that you can communicate with
them and that you&rsquo;re not a total jack-ass. Remember, we&rsquo;re dealing
with real people, treat them the way you wish to be treated. Even
though Marty was rather hostile to me during my interview, I still
treated him with respect and answered his questions honestly. Having
hobbies you can talk about in a lunch setting may also be good, but
the lives of the guys I spoke to seemed to revolve around games and
television (not really what I&rsquo;d consider hobbies).</li>
</ul>


<p>If you have any additional tips/tricks for landing a job as a game
developer, please post them in the comments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switched from Cox Cable to Verizon FiOS TV]]></title>
    <link href="http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/11/22/switched-from-cox-cable-to-verizon-fios-tv/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-22T17:25:55-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://seanmountcastle.com/blog/2006/11/22/switched-from-cox-cable-to-verizon-fios-tv</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Even though I was the first person in my neighborhood to sign-up for the
uber-fast Verizon FiOS internet service (15Mbps downstream/2Mbps
upstream), I&rsquo;ve been waiting to see how their TV offering fared before
switching. This past weekend I finally took the plunge. I decided to get
the <a href="http://broadband.motorola.com/catalog/productdetail.asp?ProductID=446">Home Media
DVR</a>
along with the basic set-top box so that we could watch DVR content from
anywhere in the house. That with the basic and movie package ends up
being $18 less than my service with Cox (which doesn&rsquo;t include a movie
package). Since I don&rsquo;t watch too much TV and my wife can live without
it, we decided against the HBO package. When the Verizon tech arrived
(&frac34; of the way through the 8am to 5pm time window they provided), he
quickly went to work switching the cable connection outside of the house
from Cox to Verizon&rsquo;s AFC ONT. Once that was done he brought the two new
set-tops inside along with the remotes (as it happens the remotes are
almost identical to the Cox DVR remotes made by Scientific Atlanta).
Before setting up the DVR box he asked where my Verizon wireless router
was&mdash;I happily obliged by going down to the basement and getting the
still sealed box that the router came in. Unfortunately, the DVR
requires the use of the Dlink router&mdash;which I refused to install as I&rsquo;m
running custom software on my LinkSys WRT54GL. Thankfully the technician
had a Motorola cable modem in his truck which he was able to use
instead. Once that was sorted out, it was a simple matter of swapping
out the existing Cox Scientific Atlanta set-tops for Verizon Motorola
set-tops. The picture quality is great, though we have no HD TVs in our
household so my impression matters little to you hard-core TV watchers.
I will say that the enhanced program guide is going to take some getting
used to after using Cox&rsquo;s for so long. It&rsquo;s not that one is better than
the other, just different. The DVR definitely needs some work. The gold
standard by which I judge DVRs is, of course, TiVo and both Cox and
Verizon have a long way to go&mdash;but the experience provided by Cox is
better than Verizon at this point. Granted, I&rsquo;ve seen numerous updates
to the DVR software rolled out by Cox during my years of service with
them (they didn&rsquo;t even have a season pass feature when I first received
it). So if you compare Verizon&rsquo;s DVR to Cox&rsquo;s initial DVR, Verizon comes
out on top. One huge difference between the Cox DVR and Verizon&rsquo;s is the
space. Verizon has a 160 GB hard disk while Cox only has 40 GB.
Recording shows on a one-shot basis is trivial with Verizon as is
recording every single instance of that show, but it gets tricky with
way too many button presses to record just the new episodes of a
particular show. My co-worker, who recently switched from Verizon&rsquo;s DVR
to a Series 3 TiVo with dual cable cards, complained that deleting shows
took too many button presses, but I&rsquo;ve not found this bothersome
(probably because I&rsquo;m coming from Cox&rsquo;s DVR and not TiVo). The home
media option, which allows you to watch DVR content in other rooms on
the standard set-top boxes is in desperate need of an upgrade. You
cannot even fast forward through recorded content on a remote set-top!
Just fixing this one issue would significantly improve the experience.
The &ldquo;on demand&rdquo; content available through Verizon appears to be much
greater in size and scope than what we had with Cox. Though this may be
colored by the fact that with the movie package you get access to Starz,
Showtime, TMC and a few other channels worth of movies, original series,
specials, etc. Overall, I&rsquo;m happy with the switch; especially because
the service is comprable if not slightly better and it&rsquo;s saving me a bit
of money each month. <strong>Updated 2006-11-24</strong>: I called Verizon about the
issue of not being able to fast forward DVR content on the remote
set-top and they refreshed both boxes which resolved the issue. So my
biggest complaint about the service has been resolved. Yay!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
